<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IaC on Xing Yahao</title>
    <link>https://xingyahao.com/categories/iac/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IaC on Xing Yahao</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Xing Yahao</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 09:21:51 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://xingyahao.com/categories/iac/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehensive Amazon EKS v1.32 Upgrade Log with Terraform and Karpenter</title>
      <link>https://xingyahao.com/posts/comprehensive-amazon-eks-v1-32-upgrade-log-with-terraform-and-karpenter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 09:21:51 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xingyahao.com/posts/comprehensive-amazon-eks-v1-32-upgrade-log-with-terraform-and-karpenter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In our organization, we encountered increasing complexity with our applications and realized that we could leverage the benefits of Kubernetes over Amazon ECS. We already had a managed EKS cluster and had deployed some internal tools on Kubernetes, appreciating the platform&amp;rsquo;s convenience. As a result, we decided to migrate all of our running applications to Kubernetes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are currently in the process of migrating about 100 ECS services to Kubernetes. A portion of our production traffic (around 20%) is already running on Kubernetes, and several internal tools are also being handled by the cluster. Before routing more critical traffic to Kubernetes, I wanted to ensure that the upgrade to EKS v1.32 would cause minimal disruption to our production services.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reducing SRE Toil with TypeScript IaC - CDK for Terraform</title>
      <link>https://xingyahao.com/posts/reducing-sre-toil-with-typescript-iac-cdk-for-terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 09:21:51 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xingyahao.com/posts/reducing-sre-toil-with-typescript-iac-cdk-for-terraform/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://storage.googleapis.com/zenn-user-upload/efd42572ae73-20241217.png&#34; alt=&#34;Efd42572ae73 20241217&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; decoding=&#34;async&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-challenge&#34;&gt;The Challenge&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While managing infrastructure resources on service providers like AWS and GCP for multiple services, our engineering team frequently needed simple infrastructure changes - creating S3 buckets, modifying CloudFront behaviors, or updating IAM permissions. While we used Terraform, developers weren&amp;rsquo;t comfortable with HCL (HashiCorp Configuration Language), creating redundant or repetitive work for SRE team.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After evaluating several Infrastructure as Code (IaC) solutions including Pulumi, AWS CDK, AWS CloudFormation, we chose &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.hashicorp.com/terraform/cdktf&#34;&gt;CDK for Terraform&lt;/a&gt; (CDKTF) because it offered:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
