<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cli on Xing Yahao</title>
    <link>https://xingyahao.com/tags/cli/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cli on Xing Yahao</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Xing Yahao</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 18:23:00 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://xingyahao.com/tags/cli/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>kubectl-execrec: Session Recording for kubectl exec for auditing and compliance with security</title>
      <link>https://xingyahao.com/posts/kubectl-execrec-session-recording-for-kubectl-exec-for-auditing-and-compliance-with-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 18:23:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xingyahao.com/posts/kubectl-execrec-session-recording-for-kubectl-exec-for-auditing-and-compliance-with-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://miro.medium.com/v2/resize:fit:700/1*xpNw34UIvHmnt-4OLl-G3Q.png&#34; alt=&#34;intro-image-created-by-chatgpt.png&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; decoding=&#34;async&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-i-created-this-plugin&#34;&gt;Why I Created This Plugin&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/keidarc/kubectl-execrec&#34;&gt;https://github.com/keidarc/kubectl-execrec&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kubernetes has built-in audit logs, but they only capture API calls, not the actual session content. When you use &lt;code&gt;kubectl exec&lt;/code&gt;, you get audit entries showing who accessed which pod, but not what commands were run or what output was produced.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For comprehensive security monitoring, tools like &lt;a href=&#34;https://falco.org/&#34;&gt;Falco&lt;/a&gt; provide real-time threat detection across containers and Kubernetes. However, these are heavy solutions designed for enterprise security teams.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing kubectl-eks-viewer Bridge the Gap between kubectl and AWS CLI</title>
      <link>https://xingyahao.com/posts/introducing-kubectl-eks-viewer-bridge-the-gap-between-kubectl-and-aws-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 09:21:51 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xingyahao.com/posts/introducing-kubectl-eks-viewer-bridge-the-gap-between-kubectl-and-aws-cli/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a developer working with Amazon EKS (Elastic Kubernetes Service), I often found myself juggling between different tools like &lt;code&gt;eksctl&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;aws-cli&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt; to manage and view EKS resources. While &lt;code&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt; provides a great interface for Kubernetes resources, accessing AWS-specific EKS resources required switching to other tools, breaking the workflow and reducing productivity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The most common task was simply checking the status of EKS-related AWS resources - What are the desired count of my nodegroups? What addons are installed? What pod identity associations exist? Getting this information required multiple commands across different tools. I wanted a single command that could show me everything at once, following the familiar kubectl patterns I use every day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing E1s the K9s Inspired Cli for Aws Ecs</title>
      <link>https://xingyahao.com/posts/introducing-e1s-the-k9s-inspired-cli-for-aws-ecs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 09:21:51 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xingyahao.com/posts/introducing-e1s-the-k9s-inspired-cli-for-aws-ecs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://storage.googleapis.com/zenn-user-upload/84798ff12916-20240531.png&#34; alt=&#34;84798ff12916 20240531&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; decoding=&#34;async&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re working with AWS ECS like me, no matter whether with Fargate or EC2, managing resources can sometimes be a challenge to using aws-cli. You might look for something that brings the ease of k9s to k8s, thee1s aims to become the tool you&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting for.&#xA;If you&amp;rsquo;re working with AWS ECS, managing resources with aws-cli can sometimes be a challenge, whether you&amp;rsquo;re using Fargate or EC2. For those seeking the ease of k9s for Kubernetes, e1s is the tool you&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting for.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
