<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Xing Yahao</title>
    <link>https://xingyahao.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Xing Yahao</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Xing Yahao</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 09:21:51 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://xingyahao.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introducing E1s the K9s Inspired Cli for Aws Ecs</title>
      <link>https://xingyahao.com/posts/introducing-e1s-the-k9s-inspired-cli-for-aws-ecs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 09:21:51 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xingyahao.com/posts/introducing-e1s-the-k9s-inspired-cli-for-aws-ecs/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re working with AWS ECS like me, no matter whether with Fargate or EC2, managing resources can sometimes be a challenge to using aws-cli. You might look for something that brings the ease of k9s to k8s, thee1s aims to become the tool you&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting for. If you&amp;rsquo;re working with AWS ECS, managing resources with aws-cli can sometimes be a challenge, whether you&amp;rsquo;re using Fargate or EC2. For those seeking the ease of k9s for Kubernetes, e1s is the tool you&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting for.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Do We Optimize Mongodb Latency and Save Money</title>
      <link>https://xingyahao.com/posts/how-do-we-optimize-mongodb-latency-and-save-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 22:21:06 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xingyahao.com/posts/how-do-we-optimize-mongodb-latency-and-save-money/</guid>
      <description>Context My organization has used MongoDB on MongoDB Atlas for over 6 years. Our backend API language is TypeScript, and we use Mongoose as our ORM. While we appreciate our tech stack&amp;rsquo;s productivity, we also find it challenging to improve server endpoint latency and balance cloud costs.&#xA;As our active users and product grew this year, we noticed a significant regression in endpoint response time. This indicated a major issue with MongoDB’s performance.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
