<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eks on Xing Yahao</title>
    <link>https://xingyahao.com/tags/eks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Eks on Xing Yahao</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Xing Yahao</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 09:21:51 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://xingyahao.com/tags/eks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehensive Amazon EKS v1.32 Upgrade Log with Terraform and Karpenter</title>
      <link>https://xingyahao.com/posts/comprehensive-amazon-eks-v1-32-upgrade-log-with-terraform-and-karpenter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 09:21:51 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xingyahao.com/posts/comprehensive-amazon-eks-v1-32-upgrade-log-with-terraform-and-karpenter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In our organization, we encountered increasing complexity with our applications and realized that we could leverage the benefits of Kubernetes over Amazon ECS. We already had a managed EKS cluster and had deployed some internal tools on Kubernetes, appreciating the platform&amp;rsquo;s convenience. As a result, we decided to migrate all of our running applications to Kubernetes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are currently in the process of migrating about 100 ECS services to Kubernetes. A portion of our production traffic (around 20%) is already running on Kubernetes, and several internal tools are also being handled by the cluster. Before routing more critical traffic to Kubernetes, I wanted to ensure that the upgrade to EKS v1.32 would cause minimal disruption to our production services.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing kubectl-eks-viewer Bridge the Gap between kubectl and AWS CLI</title>
      <link>https://xingyahao.com/posts/introducing-kubectl-eks-viewer-bridge-the-gap-between-kubectl-and-aws-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 09:21:51 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xingyahao.com/posts/introducing-kubectl-eks-viewer-bridge-the-gap-between-kubectl-and-aws-cli/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a developer working with Amazon EKS (Elastic Kubernetes Service), I often found myself juggling between different tools like &lt;code&gt;eksctl&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;aws-cli&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt; to manage and view EKS resources. While &lt;code&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt; provides a great interface for Kubernetes resources, accessing AWS-specific EKS resources required switching to other tools, breaking the workflow and reducing productivity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The most common task was simply checking the status of EKS-related AWS resources - What are the desired count of my nodegroups? What addons are installed? What pod identity associations exist? Getting this information required multiple commands across different tools. I wanted a single command that could show me everything at once, following the familiar kubectl patterns I use every day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
